GustavoPenha

guzpenha10@gmail.com

about

30 years Netherlands

links

webpage twitter github google scholar linkedin

languages

portuguese english

research

I am a research scientist at Spotify interested in search and recommendation. I currently work on the following topics: the intersection of LLMs and RecSys, discoverability in search and recommender systems, and generative & dense models for IR.

experience

2023-1-now	Research Scientist Working on search and recommendation problems.	Spotify - NL
2022-6–8	Research Intern Research on query generation for retrievability (CIKM'23).	Spotify - NL
2021-5–8	Applied Research Intern Research on explanations for Alexa (CHI'22 & CHIIR'22).	Amazon - US
2015–2018	Data Scientist Machine learning and data science projects. Tech lead of 1M+	Hekima - Brazil

selected publications

2024	Bridging Search and Recommendation in Generative Retrieval Gustavo Penha, Ali Vardasbi, Enrico P, Marco de Nadai, Hugues B
2023	Improving Content Retrievability with Controllable Query Gen Gustavo Penha, Enrico P, Maryam A, Alice W, Hugues B
2022	Pairwise Review-Based Explanations for Voice Product Search Gustavo Penha, Eyal Krikon, Vanessa Murdock
2022	Evaluating Retrieval Pipelines with Query Variations Best paper @ECIR Gustavo Penha, Arthur Câmara, Claudia Hauff
2021	On the Calibration and Uncertainty of Neural L2R Models Gustavo Penha, Claudia Hauff
2020	Probing BERT for Conversational Recommendation RecSys Gustavo Penha, Claudia Hauff
2020	Curriculum Learning Strategies for IR Gustavo Penha, Claudia Hauff

education

2018-2022	Ph.D.	Delft - NL
	Computer Science. 10 papers, 100+ citations and 150+ github stars.	
2012-2018	B.Sc. and M.Sc.	IG - Brazil
	Computer Science. MSc paper won best paper RU award at RecSys	<i>'20.</i>